We won't get anywhere without the first issue.
You're right.
It would be easier if Satoshi and Ibara were working on this too.
No, I'd rather not...
Well, I'm sure that even if we don't find the truth, it'll become history to you eventually.
History?
Alright,
then let's ask Fukube-san and Mayaka-san for assistance.
I'm curious!
What happened to my uncle 45 years ago?
Please help me find out!
Your uncle, huh?
I'm curious too.
The truth behind the story of a hero,
discovered by his successors 45 years later.
I was just reading up on that period too.
Yeah, and I'm curious about this picture.
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
If there's a meaning behind it, I'd like to know.
This is exciting!
It might be good material for the anthology if we do find out.
Investigate to your heart's content, officially for the club.
And so, investigation of the Classics Club's past
became top priority for all Classics Club members.
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
taikutsu na madobe ni
Sitting bored by the back window,
fukikomu kaze ni
A breeze blew through the room
kao wo shikameta no wa
The reason I screwed up my eyes
terekusasa no uragaeshi
Was to hide how embarrassed I was
Hyouka
aimai ni unazuku tenohira no kyou
I gave a faint nod from the edge of my palm
egaiteru jibun wa sukoshi oogesa de
The "me" I was trying to be was a bit more than I was
nani ka kawarisou na ki ga shiteiru yo
I get the feeling that something is going to change soon
kokoro ni yobikakeru kimi no sei da ne
You reached out to touch my heart; it must be because of you
kumorizora nozoita yokan
I had a feeling, looking into the clouds
te wo nobasou itsu yori mo chikaradzuyoi yuuki de
I reached out my hand, with a stronger courage than I'd ever had
hikari mo kage mo mada tookute
The light and the dark are still so far away
sore demo bokura wa
But even though they are
yasashisa no riyuu ga shiritai
We still want to know how people could be so kind
ima wa dare no namae demo nai
Now it doesn't matter whose name it may be
kagayaki no kanata he
Beyond the horizon's light,
zenbu kako ni naru mae ni
Before it all becomes the past,
mitsuke ni ikou
Let's go and find out
The Antiquity of The Classics Club and Their Glory
The Antiquity of the Classics Club and Their Glory
Sorry! Did I keep you waiting?
What's up with you, Houtarou?
Shut up!
Do you have any sense of shame?
So, did you get any data?
How about you? Any good material?
I guess.
So you'll have a good theory for us, then.
Shoot! I forgot that part.
Then let's go!
The Chitanda farming family's
mansion is one of the best in town!
Looks like you're having fun.
Of course cycling is fun!
Cutting through the air using the power of my legs! Nothing—
Not that.
I mean your high school life in general.
Oh, back to that rose-colored stuff.
My default status is "rose-colored", regardless of my surroundings.
Don't you mean "shocking pink"?
I like that!
I'll go with that, which makes you gray.
You told me that before.
Really?
But I don't mean to demean you.
My default status is "shocking pink", after all.
Nobody can dye me rose-colored.
I won't dye.
Sure you aren't already dyed?
Unthinkable.
What, Houtarou? Are you saying that because I'm busy with the Sewing Club and the Executive Committee?
Aren't you?
Nope.
I'm me whatever I do.
I don't have to be dyed.
If I wanted to demean you, I'd call you colorless.
I don't care whether you like me or not.
That's for sure!
Oh right, Houtarou. How did you do on your midterms?
I got average on everything.
Just what you'd expect from Mr. Gray.
There it is.
That's the Chitanda residence.
What do you think?
An amazing place, isn't it?
Let's go, they're waiting for us.
Yeah.
Houtarou!
Maybe a servant will come out to greet us!
Welcome!
Thank you so much for coming.
Right.
Excuse me.
Please, come this way.
Please have a seat.
Took you long enough.
But we aren't late.
Could anyone look more out of place at the head of the table?
Well then,
shall we start the meeting?
Okay!
Yep.
Yeah.
I'd like to consider what happened to the Classics Club 45 years ago.
If we can uncover the truth, I'd like to put it in this year's anthology.
First, we will distribute any materials and give reports,
followed by questions regarding the information.
Then we will present any theories,
and finally, we will consider their validity.
She's managing this meeting well.
Now for the first report—
Who should present their data first?
I take that back.
It doesn't matter who starts.
You go first, Chitanda.
Oh, you're right. Then let's go clockwise from me.
I investigated Hyouka itself.
The only part that mentions the events of 45 years ago is this preface.
A
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
I've summarized my findings on the second sheet.
A
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
A
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
A
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
A
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
A
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
A
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
A
Preface
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
The cultural festival will be held for a
spirited five days again this year.
However, as I sit in the corner of this building filled with
talk of legends, I wonder: Ten years from now,
will anyone remember that silent soldier and kind hero?
Will "Hyouka", the work he christened the day he left,
still remain? His conflict, his sacrifice, and even his kind
smile will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it is better that way. It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost, and it
will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
1.
"Senpai" left (from where?)
2.
45 years ago, "Senpai" was a hero, and 44 years ago, "Senpai" was a legend
3.
"Senpai" was a "silent soldier" and a "kind hero"
4.
"Senpai" named the anthology "Hyouka"
5.
There were conflict and sacrifices (sacrifice = "Senpai"?)
Let's start with point 1.
"Senpai" in this point refers to my uncle, Sekitani Jun.
My uncle was expelled from Kamiyama High, so his academic record ends with middle school.
2.
45 years ago, "Senpai" was a hero, and 44 years ago,
"Senpai" was a legend
Next, for point 2, I think this refers to stories growing exaggerated as time passes.
Points 3 and 5 are related.
1.
"Senpai" left (from where?)
2.
45 years ago, "Senpai" was a hero, and 44 years ago, "Senpai" was a legend
3.
"Senpai" was a "silent soldier" and a "kind hero"
4.
"Senpai" named the anthology "Hyouka"
5.
There were conflict and sacrifices (sacrifice = "Senpai"?)
"Senpai" who was normally silent and kind became a "soldier", then a "hero",
and finally he became...
a "sacrifice".
4.
"Senpai" named the anthology "Hyouka"
As for 4, I am curious about it, but let's put it aside for now.
That concludes my report.
Are there any questions?
Why did you leave out the part about how
"it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero"?
Because that was subjectivity on the part of the writer.
I think it means that the conflict wasn't as glamorous as people make it out to be.
I see.
Now then, I'd like to present my theory.
I think my uncle fought against something, then left school because of it.
Now I'd like to point out something not listed in those five points.
Here it says "a year has passed".
That would mean my uncle left the school around the time of the Kanya Festival.
On a side note,
I heard from a friend at another high school that an incident occurred at their cultural festival last year.
You mean the festival bandits.
Threatening the cashiers and stealing the proceeds.
I think people they call "delinquents" will always exist.
Perhaps the Kanya Festival may have been targeted by such people that year,
and my uncle fought them and became a "hero".
Then one of his juniors, grieving over how my uncle took responsibility and left school, wrote this about him.
Rejected.
Yeah, rejected.
It's not a good theory?
Please, tell me why!
Chitanda, do you remember what I suggested when you first mentioned writing an anthology?
Um...
A refreshment booth?
Exactly. But you told me that refreshment booths were traditionally banned.
Delinquents wouldn't be interested in the Kanya Festival because money isn't involved.
I think some would do it even without money.
Weak argument, Houtarou.
Oh? Then let's hear what you have to say.
Odd as it may seem, 45 years ago,
delinquents wouldn't target a cultural festival.
Why?
Doesn't anything come to mind when you think of the 1960's?
Tokyo, The National Diet, placards, demonstrations...
What are you talking about, Satoshi?
Student activism.
The sort of on-campus violence Chitanda-san is
talking about was almost non-existent in the 60's.
It was a time when the antagonists weren't teachers or schools, but the government and the system.
Don't talk about it like you were there.
Didn't I say I was reading up on that period?
I guess I did overlook when it happened.
I'm sorry, Chii-chan!
Is something the matter?
My information overturns your theory.
It's my turn next, so I didn't know how much I should say...
Damn you, Ibara. Making me waste energy talking...
Then I'll withdraw my theory for now.
Mayaka-san, please tell us what you've found.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
My legs are asleep.
But wow, this mansion is huge.
Do you have a pond in your garden?
We do.
Really?
I'd love to see it.
Me too!
Shall we change our location, then?
Our porch is very pleasant.
A pond, huh?
Boushu
When the time comes to plant awned grains.
Hyouka
This is an excerpt from the first issue of Alliance and Salutes.
I couldn't find any other issues of it.
It was written 44 years ago, like Chii-chan's.
Alliance and
Salutes No. 1
We are the people, and as the people, we must
continue to fight the bureaucracy to preserve our
rights. We shall never yield to the will of the
powers which oppose us.
Take, for example, the conflict in June of last year.
With the heroic leadership of the Classics Club
President Sekitani Jun and our determination
and action, the sight of those in power,
colorless, bumbling, and lost, shall be impressed
forever in our memories.
The fruits of "our determination and action."
Sure sounds like the period.
We are the people, and as the people, we must
continue to fight the bureaucracy to preserve our
rights. We shall never yield to the will of the
powers which oppose us.
Take, for example, the conflict in June of last year.
With the heroic leadership of the Classics Club
President Sekitani Jun and our determination
and action, the sight of those in power,
colorless, bumbling, and lost, shall be impressed
forever in our memories.
Alliance and
Salutes No. 1
Then I'll start my report.
First, this "We" are the students.
Next, the "powers which oppose us" and "the bureaucracy" are the teachers.
There was a battle in June of the previous year,
and the students' leader was the
Classics Club president, Sekitani Jun.
The teachers didn't know how to react to this "action".
Oh, so this character is short for "conflict"?
This Alliance and Salutes thing looks kind of shady.
Shady?
I'm not doubting it as a source,
but I get the feeling someone who looked up to the university protests wrote this.
So, does that mean anything?
Not really. Just talking to myself.
Sorry, Chitanda-san.
Then are there any other questions?
Then I'll tell you my theory.
First, Chii-chan's theory is rejected.
According to Alliance and Salutes, the incident happened in June.
As for actions resulting in expulsion,
the only thing I can think of is violence.
In other words, the group led by
Sekitani Jun took to the teachers and...
Bam. Took them down.
Though we don't know if they actually hit them.
44 years ago, something happened that impinged on the students' rights,
and they fought that.
My uncle did?
I get what you're trying to say, but...
What do you mean?
According to your theory, the teachers tried to oppress the students and the students fought back with violence.
I guess so.
Your theory is too abstract.
We can't really read into it much.
I can't really say anything more concrete, but...
Are there any inconsistencies?
Definitely.
If we believe both Hyouka and Alliance and Salutes,
then the incident was in June, while the expulsion was in October.
If the expulsion was for violence, then it would have happened right after the incident.
I guess.
I'm curious about this four-month difference.
They wrote "a year has passed" at the cultural festival, so the expulsion was in October.
Wow, you three are anal.
I think you're on the right track, though.
I agree.
Then I guess that's the end of my turn.
Yes. Thank you very much.
Then next is—
Sorry, I'm kind of hungry.
Even after all those snacks?
Sorry...
If you'd like some rice balls, I can make some.
Would you two also like some?
Chii-chan, can I help with anything?
No, I'm fine.
Really?
Yes.
Handmade!
You sure look happy.
Fuku-chan, isn't this—
Sorry Mayaka!
My research kind of invalidates your theory.
I forgot to tell you.
I see...
> The disturbance in the lab building resulting in two suspensions
and five reprimands is a striking breach of the cultural clubs' dignity.
> But they say "even a thief has his reasons", and this applies even to the
Film Society, despite its received criticism. We do not believe that the
Photography Club was completely right in its actions.
> The problem lies in that the resolution was brought about by fists.
Not putting forth effort for discussion,
holding prejudices, and coming to blows is unacceptable.
> We strongly request self-reflection of the third-year
Film Society members who attacked Sawamura Yukiko
(Shingeki Theatre Club, Class 1-D). Miss Sawamura currently
continues to visit the hospital daily.
> No violence occurred in the legendary student movement the
year before last. Though the entire student body seethed with
anger, the terms of the alliance were never broken and nonviolent
protest was maintained throughout the movement.
> This is a point of pride. We must continue in the spirit
of this legend.
(Kami High Monthly Editorial Board)
A
Is this from the Kami High Monthly?
Oh, right. Tougaito said they had 500 issues or something.
Exactly.
I looked into the back issues of Kami High Monthly that the Wall Newspaper Club published.
This is the only record that talks about what happened 45 years ago.
My summary's on the second page.
The first and last point are probably the same.
No violence occurred during the incident.
The incident affected the entire school.
During the incident "We" formed an alliance.
Nonviolent protest was maintained through the incident.
No violence occurred during the incident, so Mayaka's theory goes out the window.
And then there's "the entire school".
Assuming that's what "We" refers to, then it means the entire student body was involved.
Or if not, then someone who represented the entire student body was involved.
It's ready.
Thanks, Chii-chan!
No problem.
There's plum, dried fish, and mustard greens.
Help yourselves!
Thanks!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It's good!
Delicious!
Did your family grow this rice?
Yes.
Go ahead with any questions.
Are you sure this legendary movement is the same incident in which Sekitani Jun was expelled?
This paper alone seems suspect.
Who knows? I have no proof.
"Who knows?"
Then we can't use it to draw any conclusions.
Yeah, I guess so.
But there is indirect proof.
If the Sekitani Jun incident and the
legendary movement were different,
then they would say which legendary movement they were talking about.
Exactly! That's what I was trying to say.
Good job, Mayaka!
Can we hear your theory then?
Theory, huh...
Is there a problem?
Sorry, Chitanda-san, but I
couldn't really come up with one.
All we can do with this is turn over the Ibara theory.
And besides, a database can't draw any conclusions.
I  knew you'd say that.
Now then...
Thanks.
No problem.
What do I do?
Alright, Oreki-san, can we hear yours?
Houtarou, isn't this...
...Kamiyama High School: Fifty Years of History?
I figured the official records might have some clues.
But looking at it again, there doesn't seem to be anything worthwhile in here...
And I don't have a theory either. What now?
What's wrong, Houtarou?
Hey, did you forget what our format is?
First, start with your report...
Do I really have to do this in the first place?
Houtarou?
Oreki?
Oreki-san?
Whatever.
I give up.
What's wrong?
I forgot I was drying the shiitake mushrooms!
I have to bring them in!
Are you okay doing that yourself?
Yes, I'll be fine.
Chitanda.
Yes?
Sorry, can I use your bathroom?
Of course. It's out the room and straight ahead.
Did you get nervous or something?
Straight ahead?
Straight ahead...
I'm lost.
That's a lot of research...
I guess I'll use my head a bit.
45 years ago...
What happened to Sekitani Jun...
Four lines of research...
What ties those all together?
Think.
Student activism...
Violence...
The time difference before expulsion...
45 years ago, Sekitani Jun...
That took you a while.
Sorry.
So it's my turn now?
Sorry, but I didn't come up with a theory.
Can we skip my turn and go right to the conclusion?
Houtarou, sounds like you've got something.
Maybe.
It might work as a rough explanation.
You've figured it out, haven't you, Oreki-san?
Calm down, Chitanda-san.
Let's hear it then.
Better not disappoint us.
Alright, I'll start from the top.
First, "when".
45 years ago.
The question is what period within that.
If we go by what's in both Hyouka and Alliance and Salutes,
then the incident occurred in June, and Sekitani Jun left in October.
Next, "where".
At Kamiyama High School.
And "who"?
According to Alliance and Salutes, the main perpetrator was the president of Classics Club, Sekitani Jun.
We also know from Kami High Monthly that the entire student body was involved.
So, "why"?
The only force that the entire student body would stand up together against would be the teachers.
Like Ibara said, they were fighting to protect their rights.
And the reason for the incident was...
The cultural festival.
The reason for the incident was the cultural festival? Was that written anywhere?
No, we know that the students were
negotiating with the teachers in June,
and the cultural festival was held in October.
When you say "negotiating", are you talking about this "Meeting to discuss the cultural festival"?
That's right.
Look carefully.
There are circles and squares next to each item.
I got it!
The squares are things that happen every year, and the circles are things that only happened that year!
I looked at other years and that's most likely correct.
Why did they hold a meeting to discuss the cultural festival only once, 45 years ago?
Most likely because the student body had pressing demands.
The biggest hint lies in Hyouka.
Right here.
"In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend."
"The cultural festival will be held for a spirited five days again this year."
The key point is not that it was held, but in the fact that it lasted five days.
What do you mean?
The "five days" is the result of the hero Sekitani Jun's battle.
This is just a guess, but if we consider this principal's call for a focus on studying,
perhaps the principal decided to shorten the cultural festival to less than five days.
That would be why "the entire student body seethed with anger."
And that would be the "why" of this incident.
And so "how" exactly did it happen?
"With the heroic leadership of the Classics Club President Sekitani Jun and our determination and action."
And finally, "what" occurred?
There was no violence involved.
At worst, there was probably a boycott.
The school had no choice but to negotiate with the students,
and eventually they gave up on shortening the cultural festival.
But as a result, the hero, Sekitani Jun, was expelled.
Why was there a time difference
between the incident and his expulsion?
If they had expelled Sekitani Jun on the spot, the
student movement would have grown even stronger.
That's why they waited for it to pass.
Until after the cultural festival was over.
And that concludes my findings.
So that's what happened to my uncle 45 years ago...
That was brilliant, Oreki-san.
That was quite impressive, Houtarou.
That makes sense.
Oreki figured it out again? I can't believe this!
I was just lucky.
Are there any questions?
None here!
It sucks to admit, but I think he's right.
Then let's go with Oreki-san's theory and use this story for this year's anthology.
We'll look into more details at a later time.
We'll end here for today then.
Good work, everyone!
Thank you so much.
It wasn't just me.
No, you were the key.
Sorry to have to borrow your umbrella.
See you later.
But if that's the case, why did I cry?
konya koi ni kawaru
Tonight’s the night we fall in love
shiawase na yume de aou
Let’s meet in our sweet dreams
kitto ne mitsukete ne
Please come and find me
madoromi no yakusoku
A promise for when we sleep
mebaeteta nukumori atatakakute tomadou
I felt a growing warmth; it felt so nice that I couldn’t think
konna kimochi wo mada anata wa wakaranai no
But these feelings I have, you still don’t know they’re here
sono shisen ni wa imi nante betsu ni nai hazu
I don’t think there’s anything special in how you look at me
datte tomodachi ni shiteru no to onaji
It’s the same way you look at your friends
akegata ni kieteku chiisana negaiboshi
Fading into the dawn, my tiny wishing star
yoru no aida de no mahou
Magic that lasts only the night
konya koi ni kawaru
Tonight’s the night we fall in love
shiawase na yume de aou
Let’s meet in our sweet dreams
kitto ne mitsukete ne
Please come and find me
madoromi no yakusoku
A promise for when we sleep
Next time: The Truth of the Classics Club and Its History.
The Truth of the Classics Club and Its History