Hey, Chitanda...
Do you think the saying "What you do on New Year's, you repeat all year" is true?
Well...
I don't think it's true.
If it were true, then if you didn't do anything on New Year's, then you wouldn't do anything all year.
That seems too unreasonable.
But, Oreki-san...
I'm more curious about the situation we're in right now, rather than the remaining 364 days ahead of us
How did we get in this mess?
I wonder...
Perhaps because you drew a bad fortune?
Every day is set in stone, and we
fukuzatsu ni kamaeta kyou ga
iki wo nonde sumashiteru
Just hold our breath and live it through
mi ni oboe arun darou
I'm sure you know what I mean
kimi wa dou shitai
What do you really want to do?
nani mo nakatta soburi de
Pretending like nothing happened to you
kabau itami wa mou
The pain inside just builds up
kokorodzuyoi kurai ni
It makes me feel all the more sure
sekasunda
And urges me to go on
tsukande koboshite
Catching on, falling through
fukanzen na bokutachi ga
We've yet to learn who we are
hikatte mienai
It's so bright, we can't see
mirai no jibun wo tsukureru nara
If we can decide the kind of person that we want to be
mezameru no ma hashire
When you wake up, just start running
shinkirou wo oikoshite
Breaking through all the illusions there
kawaritai no ma hashire
When you want to change, just start running
jiyuu na wan kamu dei
Your freedom will come one day
todokisou na kagayaki to ima wo erandeikou
I hope you choose this moment and the light that lies before you
toutatsuten wo shiranai fukai sai
We don't know where we might go, so after the sigh,
kokyuu wo kasanete
Just take another breath
Sappy New Year
Sappy  New Year
Hello.
Hello, this is Chitanda calling.
Is this Oreki-san?
Yeah.
Do you happen to have any plans for New Year's?
No, not really.
I see!
Then would you like to visit the shrine with me?
Visit the shrine?
Yes.
Mayaka-san is working at the Arekusu Shrine as a shrine maiden.
I bet she looks bad.
That's not nice, Oreki-san.
Fukube-san will be going too, so I thought you might want to go as well.
And...
Is there something else?
Not really anything else in particular, but...
I'd kind of like to show my kimono off...
Okay...
It's freezing.
It definitely feels like New Year's.
Thank you very much.
People sure are wearing flowery stuff.
Thank you.
Oreki-san!
Happy new year.
I hope we can get along as well in the coming year.
As do I. Please overlook my flaws.
I'm here to show off!
Shall we go, then?
S-Sure.
Want me to carry that?
Thank you very much.
Please.
What is it?
A bottle of sake.
Our family is friends with the shrine caretakers.
I'm here to pay them a New Year's visit.
Running errands on New Year's?
Sounds like you're busy.
I was even busier during the day.
I had to be on my best behavior the whole time while my relatives were over to visit.
What did you do?
I was...
...experiencing the life of a hermit crab.
The Winds of Change
Odani Castle
Oda Nobunaga
Imagawa Yoshimoto
Mouri Shinsuke
A hermit crab?
Never mind.
Where's Satoshi?
Mayaka-san was going to give him a call.
Oh, Oreki-san!
How about we say our prayers at the main shrine first?
Well, let's see...
Please let this year be easy on my energy reserves.
Excuse me!
What is it?
Happy new year.
I'm Eru, here on behalf of Chitanda Tetsugo, who offers his wishes to you for a happy new year.
And I'm Oreki, tagging along.
Oh, Chitanda-san!
Please come in.
I'll call the caretakers.
Thank you for your hospitality.
So this is a real shrine maiden?
She's got a certain aura to her...
Happy new year.
May this year be even better than the last.
My father sends this bottle of sake.
I hope you will accept it.
So this is how rich families interact?
Thank you very much. We accept.
No, it's just a trifle.
Oreki-san, I'm supposed to say that.
I need no trifles.
Come now, please accept it anyway.
Trifling as though it may be.
It was a joke?
I was panicking!
You're from class 1-B, right?
Yes.
Fukube-kun isn't with you?
Why does she know?
Is she psychic?
This is Juumonji Kaho-san.
She's in class 1-D.
We're in the same year?!
We'd like to see Ibara Mayaka-san, if possible.
Ibara?
Oh, her?
That passage connects to the back door of the shop.
You can go through there.
Mayaka-san!
Oh, Chii-chan!
Your hair looks wonderful!
They put it on me.
Don't look.
Happy new year.
Happy new year!
That kimono is so nice!
You look beautiful!
Thank you very much.
Is it a formal kimono?
No, it's a regular one.
I won't wear my formal kimono until I start college.
My shift ends in an hour.
What are your plans?
I think I'll be a guest in the main hall.
What about Fukube-san?
He came earlier today.
But he went home to watch some drama...
The Winds of Change: Odani Castle?
I think he'll be back soon.
What are you selling here?
Fortunes.
I'm also in charge of lost kids, lost and found, and breaking change.
The regular helpers are doing a great job.
If they see anything that might be valuable on the ground, they bring it right here.
I was really busy during the day!
There were a lot of lost kids!
I didn't say anything.
A fortune sounds like fun!
Can I draw one?
Sure, go ahead.
Okay!
Oh! That purse is really nice too!
It looks so elegant!
Thank you very much.
You look happy.
I am.
Here you go.
Number 10.
Would you like one too, Oreki-san?
Here.
Thank you.
Wow!
Fortune
Number 10
Great Blessing
It's a "Great Blessing"!
That's amazing, Chii-chan!
Yes!
Number 16.
What's wrong, Oreki-san?
Nothing.
Looks like this is going to be a good year...
You got a "Future Blessing", huh?
This is the first time I've ever seen a "Misfortune" one!
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
A
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
Misfortune
Fortune
Number 16
Are you that happy about my misfortune?
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't be. You can't be happy about it...
Just give it back.
Kaho-san?
Oh, sorry, Eru.
I didn't bring you any tea...
No, that's okay. Did something happen?
One of our part-timers for today tipped a pot.
We have to remake all the dumpling soup and sweet sake.
Did they get burned?
No, they're okay.
I'll help.
No, it's okay.
You can't cook wearing that.
Then is there anything else I can do?
Could you go to the warehouse and get some sake lees?
You should see them on your left when you go in.
Sorry.
It's okay.
I'll go with you.
The warehouse, huh?
It was next to the fox statue, right?
Man, it's cold.
Let's just get this over with.
Security's pretty lax...
I hope there's a light...
Yes...
The only thing on the left is a wall.
Maybe it's deeper inside?
Maybe...
I thought it'd be an easy job, but it's turning into a pain...
Oreki-san...
Isn't this a shed?
Yeah.
You could say it's a shed, or a shack.
This is the place, right?
No, the warehouse.
Kaho-san said we had to go to the warehouse.
Oh, man! I got it wrong since I don't have a warehouse at my place!
Teehee!
Can't really say that...
You could've told me...
I'm sorry. I wasn't really sure.
There was a warehouse behind the shrine office.
Let's go back then.
Hey, the bar's off.
Guess I'll put it back.
Don't tell me...
What's wrong?
We've been locked in.
Touji
When the Sun passes its southernmost
And the Day reaches its shortest.
Hyouka
I'm sorry...
That was a dumb mistake.
It's okay. Neither of us imagined we'd get locked in.
I guess I'll try calling for someone then.
I'm going to shout as loud as I can, so cover your ears.
Wait!
Um...
Please wait!
Sorry!
But please wait!
Okay...
If you yell right now, what do you think will happen?
I suppose someone will come over here?
And then they'll take the bar off the door for us?
And how will they interpret this situation?
What do you mean?
The regulars here know me.
If one of them comes and sees us like this, they'll definitely get the wrong idea.
I'm here today representing my father.
It'd be a different story if it were another time or place,
but if I'm found in here with you today...
I'll never understand that world...
Alright.
Then what should we do?
What if someone needs something from this shed and opens the door?
They'd definitely get the wrong idea.
Kaho-san and Mayaka-san are the only ones who'd understand.
Yeah...
I've got a good idea!
Oh?
It's simple! We should just use a cell phone to contact them!
That certainly is a good idea.
Go right ahead.
I don't have my cell phone on me!
Me neither.
Oh, no!
What do we do?
It doesn't look like we can take the door off its hinges...
Um, Oreki-san..
I forgot that neither of us had a cell phone,
which is why I asked you not to yell.
But now the situation's changed.
We should just call for someone.
At this rate, you'll catch a cold!
But you're still worried someone will get the wrong idea, right?
If we completely run out of options, we can resort to that.
Until then, I'll try to think of some other way.
Oreki-san...
We can't remove the bar or unhinge it.
However, there are still four ways to get out that we haven't considered.
That many?
Yeah.
First, break the door.
Second, break the wall.
Third, dig a tunnel under the wall.
Fourth, make a hole in the ceiling.
Those are all no good!
These may be old buildings, but they're part of the shrine!
No good, huh...
Someone's coming this way!
It looks like one of the regular helpers on patrol.
He picked up a cellphone strap or something.
You can see that?
I can see quite well in the dark.
Are you some wild animal?
He's going back...
Probably to the shrine office.
The shrine office...
Hey, Chitanda...
Is it okay if I break the wall just a little?
Ibara told us that the helpers take any lost items to the office, right?
And she's in charge of the lost and found.
Right...
Let's drop something that she'll immediately know belongs to us when it gets turned in.
If we can get her to understand we're in a bind, she should come and help us.
I see!
We'll be betting on Ibara reading into the fact that it was dropped by the shed.
How about my handkerchief?
Mayaka-san's seen it a number of times.
Alright, let's go with that.
Chitanda, drop your handkerchief through that.
Okay!
We're counting on you!
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Mayaka
Fukube Satoshi
Chii-chan and Oreki are here already.
Come to the shrine office and wait there.
Juumonji-san! Happy new year!
Happy new year.
Fukube-kun, have you seen Eru anywhere?
Chitanda-san?
I just got here, so I haven't...
I see.
Sorry I can't take you there right now, but go on inside.
There's a stove in the main hall.
I'm really not good with that Juumonji-san.
Mayaka!
Fuku-chan!
I guess she's still embarrassed wearing a shrine maiden outfit.
Must be hard work with it being so cold.
Keep it up!
I'm fine.
How was the drama?
It was amazing!
I was laughing all New Year's Day!
Really?
Oh, right!
Fuku-chan, do you recognize this?
Not really.
I think Chii-chan had something like this...
It's good that you have an idea of who the owner is.
We can just ask her when she comes back.
Yeah, that's true.
No one's coming...
I thought we were onto something with the handkerchief,
but maybe that alone wasn't enough...
It's not really something that leaves an impression...
Alright, let's go with the next step.
I'll throw out my wallet.
I'll leave that with you, then.
Okay!
Look, Fuku-chan!
That's Houtarou's wallet, isn't it?
That idiot must have dropped it.
It's empty, too.
What's that?
The fortune he drew.
Houtarou drew a "Misfortune"?
This is strange...
It's completely empty...
Mayaka!
Let me draw a fortune, too.
This place's fortunes feel like they'll come true!
No one's coming...
Yeah.
Are you okay?
Yes...
I wish I'd brought my haori, though.
Haori?
The jacket I was wearing over my kimono.
I'm regretting not bringing my trench coat, too...
It's gotten pretty cold...
Sorry, Chitanda...
We might not have any other options.
Mayaka's got the items now, but I don't think she'll leave her station to come looking for us.
No, it's my fault for being selfish and dragging you along with me.
You're not being selfish. You have your own responsibilities.
That's no excuse for getting you caught up in this.
Let's just call for help.
We'll just have to put up with any rumors that spread.
I imagine Fukube-san is already here, too.
Right! Satoshi!
Oreki-san?
Chitanda, do you have a string of some kind?
A string?
About this long. Something around 50 cm or so.
That'll be enough to convey our situation to Satoshi.
How about my sandal strap?
Too short.
What about the drawstring on my purse?
No. We're going to use your purse.
What about your shoelaces?
I'm wearing laceless boots today.
If we absolutely must, we could use the string on my obi...
The string?
Yes...
Is it hard to take off?
Well, yes...
I suppose it'll take a bit of time.
Um, Chitanda...
I'm not too familiar with kimonos,
but what will happen if you take off the obi string?
The obi would kind of come off...
We can't do that then!
I guess so...
Don't we have some other string?
Why do you need a string to get Fukube-san to help?
If I remember right, there's a banner outside this shed...
I'm sorry!
Oreki-san?
Got it! A string!
Lend me your purse.
What are you going to do?
Why?!
This is definitely Chii-chan's purse!
I saw it earlier!
A handkerchief, wallet, and purse...
I wonder if this is Houtarou's misfortune at work?
This was also picked up near the shed.
What are those two doing?
And there's some dirty string tied around this, too...
String?
Yeah, look.
This...
What is it, Fuku-chan?
Mayaka, where's the shed?
That way, near the fox statue.
I'll be right back!
Houtarou! Chitanda-san! I'm coming to help!
The purse is a bag.
If the opening and the base are tied up, it means the insides are trapped.
"Trapped like a rat".
Trapped like a rat?
I didn't come up with it.
It came from a historical event.
You know the Battle of Anegawa, right?
Yes...
It's a famous story from just before that, but you might not know it.
The Siege of Kanegasaki.
When Nobunaga was attacking Asakura,
Nobunaga's brother-in-law, Azai, betrayed him.
Nobunaga's sister, Oichi, sent a bag tied at both ends to Nobunaga who was at the front lines.
Apparently the message it was meant to convey was "trapped like a rat".
I don't know how much of that actually happened, though.
I've never heard that story...
Both Satoshi and I watched a drama with that event just earlier today.
He should definitely understand the meaning behind it.
Houtarou! Are you there?
Yeah!
You're a life saver!
I was about to freeze to death!
There's some hot sweet sake waiting for you in the office.
I'm opening the door now.
Hey.
Sappy new year.
Yo. Sappy new year.
joukyou wa hikagaku teki ni
The case seems so irrational
kanjou no monta-ju
A montage of emotions
dare ga dare wo yonderu
Just who's calling who right now?
furimukeba nigeteku shisen kanjiru
When I turn around I don't feel watched anymore
ki no sei ja tsurenai yo
I know it's not just my imagination
antena wa sainou da yuusha
A heroine's antenna is her talent
datte (datte) shiritai (kimi wa chigau no)
I mean (I mean) I want to know (Don't you want to?)
seishun ondosa ima no uchi tadashite ageru yo
I'll fix the difference in how we view our youths right now
ashita kaiketsu suru nara ima demo yokunai
If it'll be fixed tomorrow, then why not fix it right now?
kimi no misuteri-
You are a mystery
toite mitai
Detective I'll try to be
shougen no himitsumeita senaka sagase (kyou mo)
Looking for the person who makes this happen to me (Again today)
kimi wa fantaji-
You are a fantasy
hikareteyukuyo tsumui
You pull me in to see
fukuranda koukishin
I want to launch an investigation
torikku wa nai no ni
Even though there isn't a trick
ki ni naru yo
I'm curious
kyoumibukai
I'm so interested
doushite
Why is that?
Next title: The Homemade Chocolates Case
The Homemade Chocolates Case