Master,
Kamiyama
Festival
another coffee please.
Um...
The truth is, I...
I have a favor I'd like to ask of you!
A favor?
Yes.
It really is a personal matter, and I have no right to ask you for help...
But would you mind
listening to my request?
Well, I'll listen, at least.
Thank you.
taikutsu na madobe ni
Sitting bored by the back window,
fukikomu kaze ni
A breeze blew through the room
kao wo shikameta no wa
The reason I screwed up my eyes
terekusasa no uragaeshi
Was to hide how embarrassed I was
Hyouka
aimai ni unazuku tenohira no kyou
I gave a faint nod from the edge of my palm
egaiteru jibun wa sukoshi oogesa de
The "me" I was trying to be was a bit more than I was
nani ka kawarisou na ki ga shiteiru yo
I get the feeling that something is going to change soon
kokoro ni yobikakeru kimi no sei da ne
You reached out to touch my heart; it must be because of you
kumorizora nozoita yokan
I had a feeling, looking into the clouds
te wo nobasou itsu yori mo chikaradzuyoi yuuki de
I reached out my hand, with a stronger courage than I'd ever had
hikari mo kage mo mada tookute
The light and the dark are still so far away
sore demo bokura wa
But even though they are
yasashisa no riyuu ga shiritai
We still want to know how people could be so kind
ima wa dare no namae demo nai
Now it doesn't matter whose name it may be
kagayaki no kanata he
Beyond the horizon's light,
zenbu kako ni naru mae ni
Before it all becomes the past,
mitsuke ni ikou
Let's go and find out
A Descendant of The Classics Club and Her Reasons
A Descendant of the Classics Club and Her Reasons
I had an uncle named Sekitani Jun.
I want you to help me
remember what that he told me.
I don't really get it.
I'm so sorry!
I got ahead of myself.
I'll explain everything properly.
My uncle went to
India seven years ago...
and has never been seen since.
Week
Without Contact
Bolstered
Black Market
Countermeasures
I was very fond of him as a child.
Kamiyama Festival
He would answer any questions I had, no matter how ridiculous they were.
It seemed like there was nothing he didn't know.
Kamiyama Festival
When I was in kinderkarten,
I learned that my uncle used to be in the Classics Club and grew curious about it.
I think it was because there was a snack we had at home that had "Classic" in the name.
Classic
What a kid.
One day, I asked him something about the Classics Club.
But for some reason, unlike other questions, he didn't want to answer me.
He didn't want to?
He didn't.
I bugged him about it until
he eventually answered me.
But when I heard his answer, I...
You?
I cried.
I don't know if I was scared
or sad, but I cried like a baby.
You cried...
My mother ran over
to calm me down.
But my uncle didn't
try to comfort me at all.
It was a big shock to me at the time, and I can't remember anything else.
But when I was in middle school, I became curious about it again.
Why didn't he want to answer me?
Why didn't he comfort me?
Since then,
I've tried everything I could think of.
Our relations with the Sekitani family broke down, but I've tried asking them about it as best I could...
But I just can't remember!
That's why I thought that the Classics Club would be my last hope when I entered Kamiyama High.
So that was your "personal reason".
But I didn't know that the Classics club was just a step away from termination.
I tried asking the teachers in the staff room,
but it's been 45 years since my uncle was in high school, and none of them knew him.
So...
why are you asking me for help?
Because...
Because I think you could find an
answer which I couldn't even imagine!
Like with that lock, or the book.
And like you did with that recruitment flyer!
I think that you can lead me to the answer!
Don't get the wrong idea.
That was all just luck.
Then let me rely on that luck!
I'm not interested.
This is an issue which could quite possibly affect Chitanda's entire outlook on life.
You think an energy conservationist like myself would take even an ounce of responsibility for that?
Not a chance.
Why just me?
I'm sure there are other people you can rely on.
Just use force of numbers.
Why don't you ask your friends too?
Oreki-san...
I do not want to go around and tell people about my past.
This isn't...
something I can ask just anyone.
Sorry.
Kamiyama Festival
I know that I'm asking a lot,
and that I shouldn't drag
you into a search for my past.
But...
You're not as nice about it as my uncle, but you answered me too.
Well, sorry I'm not nice.
I may have seen something of my uncle in you.
High school lasts three years.
You have time plenty of time to remember.
I want to remember before my uncle dies.
Dies?
Yes.
Apparently, by law, a person can be declared deceased if they have been missing for over seven years.
I see.
My uncle's family wants closure in this matter.
It isn't much, but they plan to hold a funeral.
So...
I want to keep what he told me in my heart...
when I attend the funeral.
I'm sorry.
Houtarou...
You don't have anything better to do anyway, right?
I can't take responsibility for you.
So I won't say I accept your request.
But I'll keep what you've told me in mind.
If I find anything which might
help you remember, I'll tell you.
Kamiyama Festival
If you have trouble understanding what it means, I'll help you with that, too.
Yes?
If you're alright with that, I'll help.
Thank you so much.
I will take any help you can provide.
Okay.
High school life...
isn't all rosy.
Take exams, for example.
Midterms have begun at Kamiyama High.
While they're held, all club activities are put on hold.
Of course, the Classics Club is no exception.
But since we don't actually do
anything, nothing has really changed.
Library
Kami
High
Library
Kami
High
Library
You would think we would just carry on as usual,
but since we can't borrow the room key, we're stuck.
Okay, time's up.
Midterms are over at last.
Geez...
Greetings.
I am currently in Istanbul.
I made a bit of a mistake,
so I'm lying low in the Japanese Consulate right now and haven't had a chance to see the city yet.
What did you do this time, Sis?
This trip has been such a thrill.
I'm sure that I won't regret it 10 years from now.
By the way, how's the Classics Club?
Any new members?
Also, I'm curious, so let me ask you:
Feel like writing an anthology?
The Classics Club used to publish an
anthology at the cultural festival every year.
Do you plan to continue that tradition?
I thought you might not know where to start if you did.
You won't find the old ones in the school library.
You need to search the club room.
There's an unused chemical
safebox with the back issues in it.
It's not locked.
I'll give you a call when I arrive in Pristina.
Sincerely yours, Oreki Tomoe
A chemical safebox?
Talk about good timing...
Shouman
All creation teems with life, and trees and grasses grow full.
Hyouka
Geography Prep Room
Really?
Yeah.
I brought the letter with me.
I see.
A chemical safebox, huh?
There isn't one here.
Now that you mention it,
I don't remember seeing one.
So where are the archives then?
Where could they be?
Calm down, Chii-chan!
"Chii-chan"?
Chitanda, the letter just says they're in the chemical safebox in the club room.
My sister graduated two years ago.
The club room has changed to a different classroom since then.
I see. So that's why.
So do you know where it was two years ago?
I asked our supervisor.
He said it was the Biology Prep Room.
Wow, you're actually on top of things for a change.
I'm just being efficient.
Excited, are you?
I am not.
I'm not the excitable type.
Let's go then!
Oh right, where is Fukube-san?
He's at the Sewing Club. He said something about getting ahead in summer fashion.
Oreki-san!
Biology Prep Room
Huh? It's locked...
Is anyone there?
Hey, sorry.
I had the door locked.
Are you here to join
the Wall Newspaper Club?
Biology Prep Room
No, we're not.
Is this the Wall Newspaper Club's room?
That's right.
This smell... perfume?
No, deodorant?
So, did you need something?
I'm Chitanda Eru, the president of the Classics Club.
You're Tougaito-senpai from class 3-E, aren't you?
How do you know my name?
I saw you at the Manninbashi house last year.
At the Manninbashi house?
Wait, are you Chitanda as in the shrine farms?
Yes! My father owes a lot to you.
No, no. Not at all.
I see, you're Chitanda's...
Why's he so nervous?
So is there something I can help you with?
Yes.
We heard that the Classics Club anthology back issues in the Biology Prep Room.
Biology Prep Room
Apparently, this used to be the Classics Club's room.
Oh yeah, I guess that was when I was a first-year.
In that case...
have you come across the anthologies?
No, I haven't...
Is that so? Thank you.
Don't leave!
I'm sorry, but they should be here!
Please let us search for them!
Sorry, but I already said they're not here.
But...
Guess we'll go back then.
Wait!
Don't you think he's acting suspicious?
I do.
Then don't go back!
I'm terribly sorry, but you'll
have to try somewhere else.
But we were told that
they were in this room!
If they aren't here, we'll have
to search the whole school!
The whole school...
That's not funny.
We'll only take a little of your time!
Please let us search the room!
Please from me, too.
I don't really want outsiders in the club's room...
Senpai!
This may be your club's room, but it's also a classroom, right?
Who are you?
Ibara Mayaka from the Classics Club.
Biology Prep Room
Fine.
Go ahead and look.
Just don't make a mess of things, please.
Where are the other members?
They're out today.
I was thinking about what to put in the June issue.
Executive Committee Interviews -> this year's Kanya Festival
-> someone to go buy stuff
list of stuff we need up
Club Interviews -> list of clubs to interview up
O
Info
X
Practice
News
Other
Need
- Kami High Monthly        No. 496
・ Second years - school trip
・ definite must do
・ student competition
O
Publishing: June
Sawayama interviews
1 day 1 idea
・ about work experience day
A
The paper's called "Kami High Monthly".
It's got quite a history.
We're almost at the 500 issue mark.
It doesn't look like they're here.
Kami High Monthly
It does look that way...
What do we do now?
Oreki?
Kami
High
Monthly
Active
Years
Senpai,
when you switched club rooms, was anything removed from this room?
I think I remember moving a few cardboard boxes outside.
Just cardboard boxes?
Yeah.
Which would mean...
But that's more work than I want to bother with.
Maybe I can make him do it for me.
Sorry,
but it looks like there are quite a few things in this room.
It'll take a while to look through all of it.
If you wouldn't mind, I'd like to ask our supervisor to help us perform a complete search of the room.
Would you mind?
You can't do that.
I told you not to make a mess.
But if they're not here, we back to square one!
We'll be sure to put everything back in its place—
I said no!
But...
I'm busy here!
You think I have time for your "complete search"?
Your club anthologies aren't here!
Do you understand? Get out!
Bingo.
Senpai,
we're looking for a chemical safebox.
What'd you say?
The anthologies should be in there.
If you know where it is, we won't have to bother you any further.
By the way, we're headed to the library now.
If you happen to stumble upon our anthologies after we leave, could you put them in the Geography Prep Room?
The door's unlocked.
Y-You...
You... Me...
You, what?
Fine.
I'll do that if I find them.
Thank you.
Alright, let's go.
Hey, first-year.
I don't think I got your name.
Oreki Houtarou.
I'm sorry about this.
Hey, Oreki...
Why are we waiting around here?
Energy conservation.
What's that supposed to mean?
By the way, Chitanda, what is
the Tougaito family known for?
Let's see...
They were very influential in middle school education...
A good part of their family is in education.
That makes sense.
Five minutes.
We should head back now.
Geography Prep Room
Oh look, they're here.
No. 28
Kamiyama High School
Hyouka
Classics
Club
The anthologies...
Wait a second, Oreki!
How did you do that?
What did you do?
Just a bit of blackmail.
Blackmail?
Yeah,
Ibara...
Can you keep a secret?
What?
I won't tell anyone if you say not to.
Good.
Then let's start from the top.
When Tougaito first came out of the room, he was clearly on his toes.
That's true.
Now, what about inside the room?
The window was open and he had the fan on.
But the way it was placed, it could easily
have blown his manuscript out the window.
He just wanted some fresh air.
Exactly.
Now, why did he want some fresh air?
More precisely, why did he lock the door from the inside and install an infrared sensor outside—
Hold...
Hold on,
what's this about an infrared sensor?
Oh.
There were a pair of strange boxes in the hallway.
Assuming that thing with the
antenna on the table was a receiver,
then when someone walks by
those boxes, it would sound an alarm.
How in the world did you figure that out?
Well, that would just be circumstantial evidence.
More importantly, why would he rush to get fresh air into the room whenever someone came near the room?
To get rid of a smell?
That would be the answer.
He also smelled like spray-on deodorant.
And what smell could he be so desparate to hide?
Cigarette smoke.
As an heir to a family with a stake in education,
he can't be caught doing anything illegal.
I see.
If Chitanda didn't have a cold, she
would have been able to tell instantly.
But wait, where were the anthologies?
In the chemical safebox, obviously.
O-re-ki...
I'm not making fun of you.
The chemical safebox was under that makeshift table.
He probably hides his cigarettes and lighters in there, too.
That's why he got so jumpy when I said
I wanted to call our supervisor in to search.
I knew it. You're weird.
What about me? You're calling a
standard-issue normal person weird.
Hey, everyone!
Sunflower!
Satoshi, we found the back issues of the anthology.
Hey, you did.
So this is what they're like.
They really did it all by hand 40 years ago!
Find something, Chitanda?
Looks like they used stencil printing.
Specifically, mimeograph printing.
Machines for that were invented back in the Meiji Era.
Find something?
The school probably didn't have a photocopier back in the 70's.
Oreki-san.
See?
Come with me.
They used a photocopier for this one.
Oh, I see!
This.
Hyouka.
Number two.
When I was younger, I found this.
I took it to my uncle and asked what it was.
You remember now?
Look inside.
There's something about my uncle written in it.
Something happened.
45 years ago, in the Classics Club.
The cultural festival has come again this year.
A year has passed since Sekitani-senpai left.
In this past year, he has turned from a hero into a legend.
Our conflict, our sacrifices, and even his kind smile
will fade gently into the mists of time.
No, it's better that way.
It must be forgotten,
because it was, most definitely, not the story of a hero.
Eventually, all subjectivity on the matter will be lost,
and it will all be viewed from a
historical perspective, as a classic.
One day, we ourselves will be the classics of the future.
October 13, 1968
Kooriyama Youko
"Last year" in this preface would be 45 years ago.
Which means that this "Sekitani-senpai" in the Classics Club was my uncle.
The answer which my uncle gave me must also have had something to do with the Classics Club.
Isn't that good enough?
But I can't remember what it was...
It's right there...
It's right there, but I can't!
What did my uncle tell me that day?
What happened to my uncle 45 years ago?
You'll just have to look harder.
But this says it must be forgotten.
If I look harder, I might meet with despair.
Is it some truth that is better left forgotten?
Something from 45 years ago?
It isn't?
It isn't.
It's written right here.
"It will all be viewed from a historical perspective, as a classic."
It's already history.
I see.
And while I said "look harder",
this second issue says it was "last year".
So we just have to read the first issue—
Wait, what the heck?
The first issue is missing!
konya koi ni kawaru
Tonight’s the night we fall in love
shiawase na yume de aou
Let’s meet in our sweet dreams
kitto ne mitsukete ne
Please come and find me
madoromi no yakusoku
A promise for when we sleep
mebaeteta nukumori atatakakute tomadou
I felt a growing warmth; it felt so nice that I couldn’t think
konna kimochi wo mada anata wa wakaranai no
But these feelings I have, you still don’t know they’re here
sono shisen ni wa imi nante betsu ni nai hazu
I don’t think there’s anything special in how you look at me
datte tomodachi ni shiteru no to onaji
It’s the same way you look at your friends
akegata ni kieteku chiisana negaiboshi
Fading into the dawn, my tiny wishing star
yoru no aida de no mahou
Magic that lasts only the night
konya koi ni kawaru
Tonight’s the night we fall in love
shiawase na yume de aou
Let’s meet in our sweet dreams
kitto ne mitsukete ne
Please come and find me
madoromi no yakusoku
A promise for when we sleep
Next time: The Antiquity of the Classics Club and Their Glory.
The Antiquity of the Classics Club and Their Glory