Every day is set in stone, and we
fukuzatsu ni kamaeta kyou ga
iki wo nonde sumashiteru
Just hold our breath and live it through
mi ni oboe arun darou
I'm sure you know what I mean
kimi wa dou shitai
What do you really want to do?
nani mo nakatta soburi de
Pretending like nothing happened to you
kabau itami wa mou
The pain inside just builds up
kokorodzuyoi kurai ni
It makes me feel all the more sure
sekasunda
And urges me to go on
tsukande koboshite
Catching on, falling through
fukanzen na bokutachi ga
We've yet to learn who we are
hikatte mienai
It's so bright, we can't see
mirai no jibun wo tsukureru nara
If we can decide the kind of person that we want to be
mezameru mama hashire
When you wake up, just start running
shinkirou wo oikoshite
Breaking through all the illusions there
kawaritai mama hashire
When you want to change, just start running
jiyuu na iwakan de
Your freedom will come one day
todokisou na kagayaki to ima wo erandeikou
I hope you choose this moment and the light that lies before you
toutatsuten wo shiranai fukai sai
We don't know where we might go, so after the sigh,
kokyuu wo kasanete
Just take another breath
joukyou wa hikagaku teki ni
The case seems so irrational
kanjou no monta-ju
A montage of emotions
dare ga dare wo yonderu
Just who's calling who right now?
furimukeba nigeteku shisen kanjiru
When I turn around I don't feel watched anymore
ki no sei ja tsurenai yo
I know it's not just my imagination
antena wa sainou da yuusha
A heroine's antenna is her talent
datte (datte) shiritai (kimi wa chigau no)
I mean (I mean) I want to know (Don't you want to?)
seishun ondosa ima no uchi tadashite ageru yo
I'll fix the difference in how we view our youths right now
ashita kaiketsu suru nara ima demo yokunai
If it'll be fixed tomorrow, then why not fix it right now?
kimi no misuteri-
You are a mystery
toite mitai
Detective I'll try to be
shougen no himitsumeita senaka sagase (kyou mo)
Looking for the person who makes this happen to me (Again today)
kimi wa fantaji-
You are a fantasy
hikareteyukuyo tsumui
You pull me in to see
fukuranda koukishin
I want to launch an investigation
torikku wa nai no ni
Even though there isn't a trick
ki ni naru yo
I'm curious
kyoumibukai
I'm so interested
doushite
Why is that?