I'm sorry, I couldn't find it.
You couldn't find it? That "A Corpse by Evening" thing?
I think I left it when I went to visit my relatives over summer break.
Really?
Yes...
I see. Well, help out with the posters.
Posters?
Yeah, the advertising ones.
I'm leaving for a bit.
She remembered the title...
Every day is set in stone, and we
fukuzatsu ni kamaeta kyou ga
iki wo nonde sumashiteru
Just hold our breath and live it through
mi ni oboe arun darou
I'm sure you know what I mean
kimi wa dou shitai
What do you really want to do?
nani mo nakatta soburi de
Pretending like nothing happened to you
kabau itami wa mou
The pain inside just builds up
kokorodzuyoi kurai ni
It makes me feel all the more sure
sekasunda
And urges me to go on
tsukande koboshite
Catching on, falling through
fukanzen na bokutachi ga
We've yet to learn who we are
hikatte mienai
It's so bright, we can't see
mirai no jibun wo tsukureru nara
If we can decide the kind of person that we want to be
mezameru mama hashire
When you wake up, just start running
shinkirou wo oikoshite
Breaking through all the illusions there
kawaritai mama hashire
When you want to change, just start running
jiyuu na iwakan de
Your freedom will come one day
todokisou na kagayaki to ima wo erandeikou
I hope you choose this moment and the light that lies before you
toutatsuten wo shiranai fukai sai
We don't know where we might go, so after the sigh,
kokyuu wo kasanete
Just take another breath
Chitanda-san, Mayaka.
Wildfire
Wild Fire
The cooking contest starts at 11.
Okay!
Sorry, Fuku-chan!
It turns out I have to help with making posters for the Manga Society...
Really?
In that case...
Assuming we make Mayaka go last,
you can show up at 12:10 and still make it.
Got it! I'll make it somehow!
Later!
I should go check in at the Executive Committee.
You guys can go ahead.
Well he's enjoying himself.
Conference Room
Could you take that to the gymnasium?
Of course.
By the way, aren't you going to take a look around?
All sorts of little things keep cropping up.
I've been poking my head in here and there, though.
Is there anything particularly interesting happening?
Anything interesting...
There was apparently a mysterious theft at the Go Club.
The culprit stole some go stones and left a note.
Really?
The Go Club, huh?
Yep. Though, it's probably just a hoax by the club members.
Actually, I heard from Okana that the A Capella Club had something similar happen.
Really?
Apparently they had a drink disappear from their cooler box.
Was there any written statement?
Apparently there was a weird note left in its place.
This might be very interesting...
What's that weird smile for, Fukube?
No, it's nothing.
Classics Club
Anthology
Hyouka
No. 46
On sale now
Let's do our best today, too!
What No One Noticed
Now playing
2-F Independent Film
"What No One Noticed"
Pamphlets:
50 yen
Alright, that's fine.
You'll help us out?
Yes.
Thank you so much!
You can thank me after they sell.
So, how many copies, and for how much?
Each copy is 200 yen, and we printed...
200 copies.
That's a lot.
There was a mistake with the order...
We really want to sell them, though!
I... I...
Lower it to 150 yen and give me 20 copies.
I'll sell them for 200 yen as a bundle with our pamphlet.
Okay!
What are you doing?
Give me a sample copy.
So that's what you meant!
I'm sorry, I didn't bring one with me.
Bring one with you wherever you ask.
People change depending on how you ask them.
Irisu-san...
Wh-What?
You're really good at asking people for things!
Please teach me how you do that!
Alright then.
Listen carefully.
No matter what you're asking for, you need to encourage the other party to move of their own accord.
Encourage...
In order to do that, you have to make them feel mentally satisfied at working for you.
There are various methods, but for you, the best way would be...
...expectations.
Expectations?
Exactly. Make them feel like you have expectations of them.
Make them feel...
If you can do that, they'll be happy to do whatever you ask.
Do whatever I ask...
Right.
Just don't make it seem like it's an important issue.
Not important...
Give the impression that it's a small problem for you, but somewhat important for them.
Also, one more thing.
Try to ask people of the opposite sex in a private room.
Okay.
Hurry up and go and fetch your anthology.
Thank you for the lesson!
Trick or treat!
Yay!
What are you supposed to be?
Confectionery Research Club door to door sales!
Would you like some cookies?
How much?
One bag for 100 yen!
What's that?
So cool!
Wouldn't it be great to bring something like this around with us?
How about I trade you that for 2 bags of cookies then?
I'll even throw in an anthology with it.
Really?
Bang!
Here you go then!
And as a token of thanks, you can have this too!
Wheat flour
Wheat flour?
Yay!
Trick or treat!
Bang!
Super-fast
poster drawing
game!
Watch the pride of
the Manga Society!
Magical girl
vs
Panther
"The pride of the Manga Society"?
Sounds fun.
I'm done!
Maya—
Alright, let's do this!
Sponsored by the Cooking Society
Where's Mayaka-san?
It looks like she's still busy.
I see.
Let's just trust her.
Hey, Fukube.
This is Suhara.
He's the son of a chef.
Wow, amazing.
Put up a good fight!
Later!
That we will.
Alright! The contestants today are...
Number one: Team Ajiyoshi!
Number two: Team Fata Morgana!
Number three: Team Astronomy Club!
And number four:
Team Classics Club!
Each team of 3 people will have 20 minutes per person.
After 20 minutes, you must switch out for the next member!
Talking to the person cooking at any time is strictly forbidden.
Take care to follow this rule!
What are you going to make?
Good question!
I'm making Fukube-style seafood fried rice.
Rice needs to be cooked from scratch, so I guess you'll be going third?
No, I'll go first.
I can't make seafood fried rice without rice, so I can go any time...
Do your best!
Each team will make one dish per member!
Ingredients are available on the center table on a first-come, first-serve basis.
If they run out, extra ingredients from anywhere on campus are permitted.
First contestants, at the ready!
On your kitchen!
Alright!
Let's begin then!
Wild!
Fire!
Fire.
Shuubun
When the light and dark are in balance
Hyouka
Wildfire has begun!
What kind of food will each team prepare?
This is really exciting!
Team Classics Club is cleaning out the heads and insides of each dried sardine!
What amazing attention to detail!
What do you think, President?
Very important preparatory work, Vice-President.
Team Fata Morgana has started preparing their clams!
Is he making a miso soup with daikon?
Oh no! Fukube-san!
Not good!
You forgot to peel the daikon!
Fu—
No, I can't!
That's against the rules!
Daikon...
Peel...
Peel!
Fukube-san!
He noticed!
He's going to peel each one separately?
The water is boiling over!
Team Classics Club looks like theirs is going to take some time!
Like a Möbius strip!
There we go.
Now...
We still don't know what each team is making!
Oh, Team Classics Club looks confused!
Oh, I see!
Tonjiru!
Looks like Team Ajiyoshi is making a meat sauce!
I won't make it at this rate!
First contestants, your time is almost up!
Five! Four! Three!
Two! One!
Change element!
Sorry! I only managed one dish...
Don't worry! I'll take care of this!
We're counting on you, Chitanda-san!
This is amazing!
Team Classics Club shows us how you do katsura-muki!
The true form of the daikon...
This is beautiful.
She could even clean up a riverbed with this kind of performance.
Amazing... She's already finished one dish.
Well, that's also Chitanda-san for you.
And now the Classics Club is rub-washing their rice!
They're running through their allotted 6 liters of water without a second thought!
They're prepared to die for the taste of their rice.
Look at Team Astronomy Club's second contestant!
What is that?
What are they making?
Intense fire!
Team Classics Club! Is that a giseyaki?
A taste of the old country!
Fire tower!
I've never even heard of giseyaki before.
Team Fata Morgana's yellowtail teriyaki is now at its climax!
Brilliant!
It looks like Team Classics Club has finished their giseyaki!
I'm getting hungry!
Who on earth is this second contestant of theirs?
Lady Eru of the Chitanda farming family.
Remember that!
Meanwhile, Team Astronomy Club is on an avant garde cooking streak!
The darkness envelops you!
Team Classics Club has put boiled potatoes and potato starch in a mortar!
Now they're making imomochi!
You've got a knack for this, Classics Club!
But this doesn't look good!
Doesn't look good? What?
Team Classics Club, no talking to your teammates!
No good... She doesn't get it...
It's now been 40 minutes.
Bring out your final contestant!
Fukube-san!
How did I do?
Amazing, Chitanda-san.
I had no idea you could cook so well.
I love cooking!
Yes, you did beautifully...
But...
But?
We don't have any more ingredients!
Mayaka... sorry.
And now it's time for the final contestants!
I'm done!
Excuse me!
Coming through!
Oh? Team Ajiyoshi is preparing apples for dessert!
They look like real rabbits!
Where is the Classics Club's third contestant?
Team Ajiyoshi has started carving flowers as well as rabbits!
Team Ajiyoshi is blasting ahead without regard for Team Classics Club's missing member!
Mayaka!
What's this?
A girl in plain clothes has run onto the field!
Is she part of Team Classics Club?
Mayaka-san!
Mayaka!
Is she what we've been waiting for?
It's the Classics Club!
Team Classics Club's final contestant is finally here!
But when it rains, it pours, Team Classics Club!
You're out of ingredients!
If you can't make anything, your score will of course be zero!
The Classics Club has been putting on a good show, but is this as far as they go?
Is this all that's left?
Team Classics Club has found a small onion!
What can I do?
But what can they do with one small onion?
Are they out of ideas? She's just standing there!
What will the Classics Club do?
If they don't make anything, their team will be disqualified!
What will she do?
What can I do?
What does Mayaka-san plan to do with just those ingredients?
I'm curious!
And whose fault is this?
The Classics Club's contestant isn't moving!
There we go!
Fata Morgana!
It's an omelette!
Think... Think!
Team Classics Club! Is this as far as they go?
Something...
There has to be something!
Team Classics Club is out of ideas!
They only have ten minutes left!
Will they simply wait until their time runs out?
Did someone call you just now?
There. Listen!
Team Astronomy Club is boiling bananas in broth!
Really?
Excuse me!
Yes?
Could you be quiet for a moment?
Satoshi!
It's Oreki-san!
There!
The club room!
Satoshi!
What?
What's up?
Satoshi! Get over here!
Under the window!
Right now!
Fukube-san!
What's up?
Catch this!
Nice catch!
So what is this?
Team Classics Club's first contestant is back!
Mayaka!
What?
What an unexpected development!
Could that be a bag of flour?
The rules say it's okay! All good!
Okay!
With seven minutes remaining in Wildfire, and all other teams
well under way, Team Classics Club has finally started!
What harsh conditions!
What kind of performance will we see from them?
I'm curious!
She's taking the shelled shrimp heads out of the bag!
What on earth is she making?
Kakiage...
Oh, I see! Kakiage!
Five minutes of Wildfire remain!
Hey, Cooking Club!
Where's my ladle?
The Classics Club now has a ladle!
They're now finishing their last dish!
The Classics Club is coming back!
They're making a comeback with this dish!
Kakiage over rice!
Will Team Classics Club make it?
Only one minute remains!
They're almost out of time!
She's got it!
It's in the bowl!
Three! Two! One!
And it's over!
Mayaka-san!
Way to go!
What's up?
Nothing!
We'll now be announcing the results.
The winner is...
Team Classics Club!
That was hard work.
It wasn't fried long enough.
You did an amazing job with the time and ingredients you had.
I didn't have a ladle!
If I had one from the start, it would've been perfect!
It took them at least a minute to bring it...
I'm such an idiot!
If I didn't have a ladle, I—
We're really sorry for that.
We even checked all the cookware beforehand, too...
We should have made sure right before we started as well.
I should have asked when I realized we didn't have one.
Well, it's not that important...
This is...
What?
The Cooking Society's
ladle has been lost.
Juumonji
A note from the thief?!
The Cooking Society's
ladle has been lost.
Juumonji
joukyou wa hikagaku teki ni
The case seems so irrational
kanjou no monta-ju
A montage of emotions
dare ga dare wo yonderu
Just who's calling who right now?
furimukeba nigeteku shisen kanjiru
When I turn around I don't feel watched anymore
ki no sei ja tsurenai yo
I know it's not just my imagination
antena wa sainou da yuusha
A heroine's antenna is her talent
datte (datte) shiritai (kimi wa chigau no)
I mean (I mean) I want to know (Don't you want to?)
seishun ondosa ima no uchi tadashite ageru yo
I'll fix the difference in how we view our youths right now
ashita kaiketsu suru nara ima demo yokunai
If it'll be fixed tomorrow, then why not fix it right now?
kimi no misuteri-
You are a mystery
toite mitai
Detective I'll try to be
shougen no himitsumeita senaka sagase (kyou mo)
Looking for the person who makes this happen to me (Again today)
kimi wa fantaji-
You are a fantasy
hikareteyukuyo tsumui
You pull me in to see
fukuranda koukishin
I want to launch an investigation
torikku wa nai no ni
Even though there isn't a trick
ki ni naru yo
I'm curious
kyoumibukai
I'm so interested
doushite
Why is that?
Next time: The Juumonji Incident.
The Juumonji Incident